Kevin W. Hoffman

Product Manager • Designer • Developer

Website: kevinwhoffman.com

• Email: kevin@kevinwhoffman.com

Twitter: <u>@kevinwhoffman</u>
Location: Pittsburgh, PA

% Introduction

Hi, I'm Kevin. Most recently I served as Product Manager of GiveWP—a WordPress donation plugin with over 100,000 active installs. With ten years of experience developing websites, products, and SaaS platforms, I'm looking to continue my work in product management as part of a team that prioritizes diversity, accessibility, and quality.

Experience

Impress.org, LLC

▼ Product Manager (Mar 2019–Nov 2020)

- Led product development of <u>GiveWP</u>—a WordPress donation plugin—and its <u>ecosystem of 30+</u> add-ons.
- Led product development of <u>WP Business Reviews</u>—a WordPress reviews plugin—which involved API integration with social media platforms.
- Planned and managed <u>six-week development cycles</u> for WordPress plugins and a SaaS platform.
- Established a <u>feedback system</u> to aggregate feature requests, bug reports, and integrations submitted by employees and users.
- Coordinated execution with Marketing, Support, and Customer Success teams throughout development.

▼ Senior Web Developer (Oct 2017–Mar 2019)

- Developed plugin, website, video, and graphics for WP Business Reviews.
- Wrote documentation for internal processes and customer-facing products.
- · Automated builds and deployments via GitHub actions.

▼ Web Developer (Oct 2016–Oct 2017)

- · Programmed WordPress plugins that added new features and integrations to GiveWP.
- Triaged feature requests and bug reports submitted by customers and the open source community.

Kevin W. Hoffman Design, LLC

▼ Owner (May 2013-Present)

- Design, develop, and manage complete websites for clients in need of a web presence with a content management system.
- Provide photography, videography, and graphic design to supplement websites.

Acosta Marketing Group

▼ Senior Web Designer (Jun 2012–May 2013)

- Designed responsive microsites for brands such as Starbucks, Seattle's Best Coffee, and Heinz Ketchup to promote seasonal offerings.
- Worked within the constraints of style guides to create content that fit in seamlessly alongside the parent brand.

Skills

- · Product management of complex software including projects that span multiple packages and repositories
- Understanding of the relationship between design and code and the tools necessary to bring the two together (Figma, Storybook)
- Management of shared component libraries and design systems (Figma, Storybook)
- User interface design and prototyping (Figma, Sketch, Photoshop)
- DevOps contributions that streamline product development and deployment (GitHub actions, shell scripts, Slack automations)
- Creation of media-rich presentations to pitch new products and features
- Programming (HTML, CSS, Sass, JS, TypeScript, React, PHP, C#)
- Open-source software development (contributions to the WordPress project)
- Version Control (Git, GitHub)
- Video production and motion graphics (Final Cut Pro X, After Effects)

Education

Drexel University

▼ Bachelor of Science, Digital Media (Sep 2005–Jun 2009)

- · Drexel University SIGGRAPH Chapter
- · Pennoni Honors College

References are available upon request. I look forward to discussing this opportunity with you soon, and invite you to visit my personal site at kevinwhoffman.com. Thank you!